Jared Ryan

jaredryan.netlify.app | github.com/jaredryan jryantennis@gmail.com | 559-348-3595 | Jupiter, FL (Remote)

Summary

Fullstack software engineer. 5 years of experience, mostly w/JS languages. Better at frontend.

Technical Traits: Curious to try new things. Tackles big projects boldly and systemically. Enjoys PR reviews and clean code. Design-oriented / client-focused.

Personal Traits: Organized. Empathetic. Good listener. Outspoken. Personable.

Skills

Frontend: JavaScript, TS, React, HTML, CSS, Responsiveness, Accessibility, Tests, Performance **Backend:** Node, MongoDB, SQL, RESTful APIs, Docker, Kubernetes, Tests, Automation **Soft:** Agile, discover client needs, technical planning and documentation, coordinating and following up on work, demos, pairing, mentoring, independent...but knows when to seek help

Experience

MANTL, Activations, Software Engineer II

Jupiter, FL (Remote) | 2021 - 2023

- Mentored a few engineers on frontend work and owned crucial frontend features, gaining a reputation for good PR reviews, careful testing, troubleshooting, good design and flows
- Co-led work on introducing a design-component library that integrates with the prior one
- Co-led work on an automated testing pipeline: the pipeline itself, testing framework, database seeding / cleanup, tests, and teaching others how to contribute
- Proactively worked with cross-team stakeholders to identify, prioritize, and complete work to reduce number of days on our "activation" flow (time from request to completion)

IBM, Cloud Pak for Data, Software Engineer II

San Jose, CA | 2019 - 2021

- Refactored entire frontend for user management, which evolved to a small leadership role as work expanded and required additional engineers
- Architected user management technical solutions with product and backend lead, considering security, performance, sizing, business value, and usability
- Co-created conceptual models and user flows with design, providing guidance on attributes and relationships between users, roles, permissions, and groups
- Planned projects with 1, 3, and 6 month cycles, executed via Agile in 2-week sprints

IBM, AppID, Software Engineer I

Austin, TX | 2018 - 2019

- Prototyped a fullstack application in React, Node, and Python showcasing all uses of ApplD, which was leveraged for sales pitches and demos
- Adapted to multiple technologies and protocols to quickly debug issues: OAuth, OpenID, Node, Angular, Java, Android, Swift, Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins, Github, Zenhub

NTR, Web Developer

Berkeley, CA (Remote) | 2018 - 2022

- Sole developer on a web app for collecting, grading, and anonymizing peer feedback, which has been used by 600 students, across 7 schools, generating 6K evaluations
- Collaborated with non-technical UC Berkeley professor to define product requirements and designs, then again for updates and new features over the 4 years before handoff
- Learned troubleshooting without access to clients, and maintenance practices

Education